Oh h1 Rules

3 In a Row
If two consecutive blocks are same color, than surrounding blocks must be opposite color.
If two blocks of same color are separated by a block, that block must be the opposite color

Same Number of Each Color per Row/Column
If only one open block remains, then it must be the color that is "short"
In a grid of size n, if n/2 blocks are the same color, the rest must be the opposite color

No Duplicate Rows/Columns
If selecting a color for a block - and finishing that row/column, cause it to be a duplicate row/column, then the selected block must be the opposite color

Illegal Move
If selecting a color for a block ???

If three spaces remain and two must be the same color but that would result in three in a row, then the third space must be that color while the two adjacent are of each color.